You've just clicked buy now online, that satisfying click.
But have you ever really thought about what happens right after,
you know, beyond the shipping label?
Yeah, there's this whole hidden world, isn't there?
An incredibly complex optimization process,
just trying to get that package to you.
Efficiently, affordably, it's fascinating.
And today, we're taking a deep dive into something
right at the core of it all, order batching problems.
It sounds a bit technical, maybe.
It does, yeah.
But trust us, it's kind of the secret sauce
behind how fast affordable deliveries
actually work these days.
Absolutely.
And our mission for you, the learner,
is really to cut through the jargon
you might see around this.
We want to pull out the key nuggets of knowledge
from what is, honestly,
a pretty dense academic review we looked at.
We hope to uncover some surprising stuff,
give you maybe an aha moment about the logistics that,
well, that power our modern world.
And yeah, dense academic review isn't an exaggeration.
It's a big stack of research really laying out
where things are now and where they're going
with optimizing how items get picked in warehouses.
Packed with detail.
So our job is to make it clear, make it compelling,
maybe even a little bit entertaining for you.
So let's start right at the beginning.
What is order batching?
Good question.
Simply put, it's an optimization problem
in supply chain management.
Think of it like grouping several different
customer orders together into one batch.
Before anyone starts picking.
Exactly, before the picker even starts moving.
Then all the items for that whole batch,
they get collected together
on just one continuous trip through the warehouse.
Okay, so it's different from the old way,
like one picker, one order at a time.
Right, that's called strict order picking.
This is batching multiple orders.
And why is that better?
What's the inefficiency it solves?
The research specifically mentions
it's good for B2C, right?
Business to customer.
Yeah, good point.
The problem with strict order picking one order,
one trip is basically wasted travel.
Lots of walking back and forth
for potentially just one item.
Batching says, hey, if the picker's
already going down an aisle,
why not grab items for several orders
from that same aisle or nearby aisles all at once?
Makes sense.
And it's especially good for B2C
because you often have lots and lots of small orders,
maybe just one or two items each.
Grouping those makes way more sense than say B2B,
where you might be picking whole pallets of stuff anyway.
Okay, and digging through this research,
I mean, one number really jumped out at me.
It said, implementing order batching
can cut warehouse travel time by up to 35%.
That's a huge number, isn't it?
It's staggering.
Is there a catch, a trade-off,
or is it just pure efficiency gain?
And how does that affect the price I pay?
It really is a remarkable gain.
I mean, sure, there might be a little more complexity
maybe in sorting the items out after picking,
depending on how you do it.
But the reduction in travel time,
it usually blows any minor downsides out of the water.
Okay.
And when you think about the money involved,
wow, the picking process itself,
just finding and grabbing items,
it's a massive cost for warehouses.
This review suggests it can be up to 60%
of all the labor activities.
60%.
Yeah, and maybe more than half
of the total operational costs.
So if you can slash travel time by 35%
for something that costs that much.
It's huge for the bottom line.
Absolutely.
It means big savings for companies,
which, you know, can hopefully translate
into the better prices or faster shipping for you.
60% of labor.
Really hammers home why this order batching thing,
even if it sounds niche, is so critical financially.
And it's not just one simple decision, is it?
The research talks about different levels.
Order batching itself is mostly an operational decision
that's like the day-to-day, short-term stuff.
How do we run things today?
Okay.
But it's heavily influenced by strategic decisions,
the big long-term choices.
Yeah.
How do we even design the warehouse layout?
What software do we buy?
I see.
And then there are tactical decisions
in the midterm things.
Like, where should we store which products
within this layout to make picking easier?
It's all connected.
A whole web of decisions.
So for this deep dive, where are we focusing?
Because that sounds vast.
Good point.
We're mainly looking at the most common setup
described in the research.
Manual picking systems.
So humans doing the picking.
Okay.
Usually in standard rectangular warehouses.
The ones with parallel aisles going one way
and maybe cross aisles connecting them.
And pickers typically start and end their routes
at a specific spot called the depot.
Got it.
So if batching is grouping, how does that actually work?
Is it just randomly throwing orders together?
Or is there more to it?
An art of the batch, as the source puts it.
Yeah, there's definitely an art,
or maybe a science to it.
It's not just random grouping.
There are several really critical tasks
involved in the whole picking process
that affect, or are affected by,
how you make those batches.
Okay, like what?
Well first, the researchers highlight
something called the waiting task.
Waiting?
Yeah.
Deciding how long an available picker should actually wait before starting a new picking route.
Why wait? Wouldn't you want them to just go?
You'd think so, right. But this waiting time, often called a time window,
has a logic. The longer you wait, the more new orders arrive.
Ah, okay.
So waiting might allow you to create a better, more compact batch with items that are closer
together in the warehouse, leading to a shorter overall route later.
Interesting. So potentially a short wait saves more time overall.
Potentially, yes. The research says this waiting task can have a profound impact on performance.
But here's the kicker.
What?
It's also, surprisingly, the least studied task. This huge review paper we read.
It found only three papers that even looked at the waiting task explicitly.
Wow, that seems odd. If it's so impactful, why ignore it?
That's one of the big questions the review raises. Okay, so beyond waiting, what else?
Right, other pieces of the puzzle.
Next up is the selecting sequencing task. This is about which batch to pick next,
assuming you have multiple batches ready to go.
So, like, prioritize the urgent ones.
Exactly. Do you just pick the single most urgent batch selecting,
or do you figure out an optimal order for picking a whole list of waiting batches sequencing?
Then, if you have multiple pickers, there's the assigning task.
Which available picker gets assigned the next batch?
You want to try and balance the workload right, keep everyone busy but not overloaded.
Makes sense. And the actual path they walk.
That's the routing task. Huge deal. Determining the exact sequence of locations the picker visits
to get all the items in their assigned batch. This directly controls the travel distance and time.
Probably the most visible part, I imagine.
Very possibly. And finally, there's the sorting task. How do you handle the items once picked?
Do you just throw everything from a batch into one big bin and sort it all out later?
Pick and sort. Or do you have, say, separate totes or bins on the picking cart,
one for each customer order, and sort the items into the right bin as you pick them?
Sort pile pick.
So many decisions within the picking process itself, even after you've made the batch.
How do they even measure if they're doing a good job, beyond just faster?
Yeah, good question. In optimization, you need clear goals, right?
We call these objective functions. Specific things you're trying to maximize or minimize.
Like KPIs.
Exactly like KPIs. So often it's about time. Reducing the picking time itself,
or the waiting time we talked about, or the total time an order spends in the
system that's throughput time. They also might want to minimize being late,
tardiness, or even being too early, earliness, if delivery slots are tight.
Right.
Then there's distance. Pretty straightforward. Minimize how far pickers have to walk or drive.
Often, distance and time are kind of equivalent if travel speed is constant.
True.
Cost, obviously. The direct economic impact.
And if you've got multiple pickers, workload balance is important.
Trying to give everyone a fair share of the work may be measured by number of orders,
number of items, or distance traveled.
Got it. So multiple ways to define success. And I guess the batches themselves have limits,
right? You can't just group infinite orders.
Exactly. There are physical constraints. A batch might be limited by total weight,
total volume, the maximum number of individual items, or even just the maximum number of
separate orders you can manageably handle on one cart.
Right. Physical reality kicks in. Okay, so with all these variables, waiting, sequencing,
routing, objectives, constraints, it sounds incredibly complex.
How do researchers even talk about this consistently?
That's where this new taxonomy comes in, the classification system
proposed by the researchers in this review. They see it as a way to map out the territory,
like a compass.
Okay. What are the main directions on this compass?
It mainly classifies problems along two key lines. First is the availability of information.
Meaning?
Is it offline, meaning you know all the orders you need to process right at the start,
like you get a list for the whole day?
Okay, like a planned schedule.
Right. Or is it online, where orders are arriving dynamically in real time,
like on a busy e-commerce website, new orders constantly popping up?
Much more unpredictable.
Definitely. The second big distinction is the number of pickers. Is it just a single
picker scenario, or are there multiple pickers working simultaneously in the warehouse?
Okay, offline, online, and single, multiple pickers. That gives us a grid, I guess.
Pretty much. And using this grid, this taxonomy, led to some genuinely surprising
findings when they reviewed all the existing research.
Okay, let's unpack those. What jumped out?
Well, first, get this. Using their taxonomy, they identified 36 possible combinations,
36 different types of order-batching problems based on those factors and others.
36 variants? Okay.
An incredible 18 of them, fully half, have apparently never been studied in the academic
literature, just blank spaces on the map.
Half, wow. It's a lot of unexplored territory.
Isn't it?
And then there's this reality gap.
The review found that most academic research, like a huge chunk, 74% of the papers they
looked at focuses on the offline single picker scenarios.
The simpler case, maybe?
Planned lists, one worker?
Arguably simpler, yeah.
But think about modern e-commerce.
Big warehouses, orders pouring in constantly, lots of pickers moving around.
Right, that sounds like online, multiple pickers.
Exactly.
The most realistic scenarios for today's world are typically online.
Single picker problems, but that's where the least research has been done.
There's a huge disconnect.
So academics are mostly studying a version of the problem that's less common in the real
world.
That seems to be a major finding, yeah.
A big opportunity for future research to catch up with practice.
And what about that waiting task again, the overlooked gold mine?
Still overlooked.
Despite being shown to deeply influence how well everything works, it remains by far the
least studied activity.
Remember, only three papers even addressed it directly.
It feels like a massive missed opportunity for optimization.
It really does.
So how do researchers typically try to solve these problems, even the simpler offline ones
they focus on?
What methods do they use?
Mostly, the papers combine heuristic and metaheuristic algorithms.
Okay, unpack those terms a bit.
Sure.
Think of a heuristic as a smart shortcut, a rule of thumb.
In a huge warehouse, you can't possibly calculate every single possible route or batch combination.
It would take forever.
Right.
Too many options.
So a heuristic is a clever strategy to find a pretty good solution quickly, even if it's
not guaranteed to be the absolute perfect best one.
Okay.
A practical approach.
And a metaheuristic is kind of like a strategy for finding better heuristics or combining
them smartly.
High level strategies to guide the search for good solutions.
Gotcha.
Any specific popular methods?
For the routing part, figuring out the path, one method is incredibly popular.
The S-shape heuristic.
S-shape.
Like the letter S.
Literally.
The picker basically snakes through the aisles in an S pattern.
It was used in 62 out of the 125 papers they surveyed that dealt with routing.
It's often quite efficient at covering aisles without unnecessary backtracking.
Simple, but effective, I guess.
So if the real world problems are complex, online, multi-picker, and often unstudied,
what's next?
How do we tackle those?
What does this all mean for us, for the listener?
Well, it points towards needing even smarter algorithms.
The review mentions math heuristics.
Math heuristics, a hybrid.
Exactly.
Kind of blending the strengths of precise mathematical optimization, which can find
the perfect answer, but only for smaller, well-defined parts of the problem with those
clever, fast heuristics that can handle the bigger, messier picture.
Combining the best of both.
That's the idea.
Using precise methods where possible, and smart shortcuts elsewhere, to tackle these
really complex, realistic problems.
It shows this field is booming, because companies need these solutions.
The economic stakes are high, but it's also clear that we're still just scratching the
surface of the most complex scenarios.
There's this massive opportunity, for researchers and for companies, to really dive into those
18 unstudied variants.
Especially the joint problems.
Yes.
Problems that don't just look at batching and isolation, but optimize batching alongside
sequencing the batches, assigning the pickers, maybe routing, and especially incorporating
that overlooked weighting task.
It feels like the future is about connecting more dots.
Absolutely.
And the research even hints that future work might integrate other warehouse tasks, like
sorting more deeply, or even coordinating picking with shelf restocking, all into one
giant optimization problem.
It's going to get you more interconnected.
Wow.
So we started with just clicking, by now.
Yeah.
A simple click.
And now, hopefully, you have a much deeper appreciation for that incredibly intricate
dance of optimization happening behind the curtain.
You've gotten a shortcut, really, to understanding a super critical bit of logistics.
The why and how behind getting stuff from warehouse shelf to your door efficiently.
This deep dive, we hope, gave you a more nuanced view.
Not just what order batching is, but why it's such a constant puzzle.
The surprising bits that often get missed, and, you know, the huge frontiers still left
to explore.
Definitely.
So let's leave you with a final thought.
As e-commerce just keeps growing like crazy...
And remember, half of these potential order batching problem types haven't even been properly
studied yet.
What kinds of innovations in warehouses might be coming down the pike?
Things that could totally revolutionize delivery times, costs, maybe even the kinds of things
we can get delivered almost instantly.
And how does robotics fit in?
Will mixing human pickers and advanced robots make this intricate dance simpler, or even
more complex?
What completely new optimization challenges will pop up next?